[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
on May 30th of this year I made an
Instagram post and I said men bashing
modern female glute training methods is
thinly veiled misogyny and I said
imagine being so fragile that you get
insanely triggered when you see an
exercise being performed unfortunately
this is now the norm when many men watch
women training is happening much more
frequently we need to draw attention to
this and Define it for it to stop this
includes the bashing of Kickbacks
abduction exercises band work heavy hip
thrusts and high frequency glute
training in the comments section below
you'll not undoubtedly witness dozens of
men attempt to justify downplay these
practices I need women to chime in here
and share their experiences because it's
gotten out of hand in general women are
the experts in glute training not men
the people who become the experts at
something are the ones who care about it
the most prioritize it the most and
experimented with the most one study
showed that men perform nine sets of
glued exercises per week whereas women
perform 40. most male lifters have never
performed a single set of hip thrusts
Kickbacks or any abduction exercise
similarly most have never used elastic
resistance band for a quick glute
workout and despite this complete
ignorance it doesn't stop them from
chiming in and telling women how they
should lift in order of most to least
egregious numerous men are one bashing
the way women train when women are in
fact training exactly how they should be
training for their goals to providing
incorrect unsolicited advice to women in
the gym pertaining to things with which
they have zero experience and three
exhibiting extreme hypocrisy it's far
more rampant than you guys can imagine
and comments on social media are getting
more hostile and frequent for some
bizarre reason men think that they can
tell women what their training goals
should be and they think that women
should be training just like them as if
women's training schedules should
consist of one weekly chess day back day
shoulder day arm day and a quad and ham
day containing zero glute isolation work
it seems that most men cannot understand
that women have different physique goals
than men which requires them to train
differently in 31 years of studying
strength training I can't think of a
single time where I saw a woman bashing
10 typical male training methods or gym
attire they ignore the drop armhole tank
tops the hoodies the MC Hammer pants the
leggings and the fanny packs they ignore
the five upper body days with only one
leg day that commonly gets skipped they
ignore the fact that men perform five
exercises including isolation work for
the pecs the lats the delts and the
Bison tribes but zero isolation work for
the gluteus maximus or medius two really
important muscle groups they ignore the
one rep max bench presses bouncing the
bar off the chest and the way too heavy
quarter squats and leg presses they
ignore the constant flexing in the
mirror and lifting the shirt up in
between every single set to make sure
the six-pack is still there they mind
their business and let Bros be Bros
however every single day women have to
deal with men mansplaining and worse
insulting them for performing a variety
of glute exercises for training the
glutes multiple times per week and for
performing heavy hip thrusts men seem to
be okay with variations of squats
deadlifts lunges split squats step UPS
leg press reverse hypers and 45 degree
hypers for glutes maybe because these
have been around for longer or because
most of them are stretch position
exercises but they lose their minds when
they see women performing hip thrusts
glute Bridges frog pumps Kickbacks
seated hip abduction and cable staining
hip abduction ornate band glute exercise
and most of these are more modern
squeeze position exercises bear in mind
that Bros do tons of concentration curls
rope tricep extensions Cable Crossovers
and lateral raises all squeeze exercises
so this is massively hypocritical
moreover hip abduction and bent leg hip
extension movement patterns are
necessary to optimize a woman's physique
particularly for upper glute development
the primary role of the glute medius is
to abduct they also bash female
fitfluencers for their gym attire and
their booty poses but their outfits are
over the top too and they're constantly
flexing in the gym Bros are arguably
more absurd than booty influencers if
women acted like men every time a man
perform the following movements here
would be the response dealt raises bro
just shoulder press those literally do
nothing flies and crossovers dude just
bench and incline press those are
literally worthless curls and tricep
extensions laugh my ass off drop the
useless wimpy arm movements and just do
chin UPS close grip bench and dips like
a real man deadlifts dumbest exercise in
existence injury waiting to happen any
one rep max attempt that's all ego bra
one rep literally does nothing drop the
weight and do at least six reps
preferably 12. and here's what's
craziest about this phenomenon you'll
have a hundred women comment that they
saw better results in terms of glute
development when they started doing hip
thrust or using bands but men will never
acknowledge this they'll write them off
as clueless and dismiss their anecdotal
experience moreover men think they can
deny reality you'll hear Bros commonly
say the women with the best glute
development all focus on squats that's
not true not by a landslide the women
with the best glute development in the
world are bikini competitors and fitness
influencers most of them prioritize hip
thrusts and perform a fairly equal
amount of vertical hip extension
exercise like squats lunges step ups and
deadlifts horizontal hip extension
extras like hip thrust glute Bridges
back extension Kickbacks and lateral
glute exercise like C seated standing or
side lying hip abduction they perform
around 36 steps per week for glutes and
utilize free weights machines and bands
they perform a ton of glute isolation
work because if they relied solely on
squats and deadlifts their quads hams
adductors and Erectors could get
overdeveloped compared to the glutes
they're trying to grow the glutes more
than the legs I'm going to repeat that
than the legs in addition they'd
experience significantly more pain and
injuries if they solely perform squats
and Deads as these can be hard on the
knees hips and low back they use bands
because they're awesome for isolating
the glutes and providing penalty free
volume that doesn't make you sore and
it's a nice complement to free weights
you'll never I repeat never see a male
hater talk about actually programming
either though bash hip thrusts or
kickbacks or abduction but if if you ask
them what what's an optimal glute
training program they won't answer you
this is because one they really don't
have the slightest clue about glute
training in two they'd expose themselves
as frauds for example if they said to
just squat lunge an RDL for four sets
twice per week any law logical person
would realize that hip drives and
kickbacks and abduction could be added
to this same program for even better
results and if you ask them about their
own training program you'd see that they
perform isolation movements for every
muscle including buys tries delts lats
traps ABS quads hands and calves
apparently it's okay to isolate any
muscle except for the glutes LOL Bros
pretend that hypnos are dangerous but
everyone in the world knows that squats
and deadlifts are far more dangerous
this isn't even an argument we have
research now showing that hypnos
continue to build the glutes if added to
a program consisting of leg press and
stiff legalis this provides evidence
that the hip thrusts don't do nothing
and there's more positive research on
the way however male haters don't care
about research they don't care about
anecdotes they don't care about reality
the truth is far more appalling Bros
cannot stand that women figured out a
better way to train a certain body part
glutes more than them it drives them
absolutely crazy to the point where men
are making up their own physics and
fabricating studies to pretend like hip
dose are an effective or claiming that
bands don't require any muscular
attention to stretch them in some memory
men do not possess the glute training
expertise that women do and their
training advice is downright laughable
men are bashing female glute training
methods providing wrong unsolicited
advice mansplaining and exhibiting
extreme hypocrisy and it has nothing to
do with science or reality and
everything to do with misogyny and it
won't stop until people start speaking
up about it let's start calling a spade
a spade and dealing with this issue for
those of you who don't think this is a
big deal read the comment section below
to see what women have to deal with
every single day and decide for yourself
it's if it's acceptable or not how would
men like it if women bullied and shame
them every time they did a max bench
press or a set of curls or lateral
raises or for training upper body five
times more often than lower body and it
wasn't based on science but solely due
to miss Andre exactly Bros quit telling
women how they should train they know
more than you